chessable.com 2019-03-09

# Privacy Policy - Chessable.com

For the purposes of the data protection legislation, Chessable Limited ('we' or 'us') is the 'data controller' (the company who is responsible for, and controls the processing of, your personal data).

If you are aged 16 or under, you must ensure that we have your parent/guardian's permission before you provide any personal information to us (including creating an account).

## Personal data we may collect about you

We will obtain personal data about you such as your name, address, phone number, and email address when you create an account on Chessable for purchasing digital chess content and subscriptions.

Additionally, we will obtain your personal data when you send us feedback, or contact us for any reason.

We may monitor your use of Chessable through the use of cookies and similar tracking devices. For example, we may monitor how many times you visit, which pages you go to, traffic data, location data. This information helps us to build a profile of our users, which we use to help improve the way we deliver services to you. Some of this data will be aggregated or statistical, which means that we will not be able to identify you individually. For further information on our use of cookies, please see our Use of Cookies section below.

Basically,

This describes the types of your personal information we might hold and process.

## Payment Data

We do not store credit card details nor do we share financial details with any third parties. All payments made on the website will be processed by a third-party credit card processors, PayPal, and Stripe which encrypts all payment transactions. All such transactions will be governed by their privacy policies at <https://www.paypal.com/uk/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full> and <https://stripe.com/gb/privacy>.

Basically,

We don't store your payment details, which are securely processed by our payment facility providers.

## How we use your personal data

When ordering digital chess content, subscriptions you will be asked whether you agree to this Privacy Policy, and by indicating that you agree you consent to our using your information for the following purposes:

  * facilitating subscriptions, and digital chess content purchases;
  * billing you;
  * to help us identify you and any accounts you hold with us;
  * administration;
  * research, statistical analysis and behavioural analysis;
  * customer profiling and analysing your purchasing preferences;
  * marketing—see 'Marketing and opting out', below;
  * fraud prevention and detection;
  * customising Chessable and its content to your particular preferences;
  * to notify you of any changes to Chessable or to our services that may affect you; and
  * improving our services.

Basically,

We need to use your personal data for a number of reasons. They’re listed here.

## Marketing and opting out

If you have given permission, we may contact you by email about products we think may be of interest to you. If you prefer not to receive any direct marketing communications from us, you can opt out at any time. For more details see 'Your rights', below.

## Disclosure of your personal data – to other Chessable users

You control the extent to which any personal data is shown to any other Chessable users. You control this by means of the variable settings in the ‘profile’ tab in the ‘gear wheel’ settings option accessed through clicking on your username and the top of the screen on Chessable. Please check the default settings are to your liking before proceeding to use Chessable.

Basically,

You control how much you share with other Chessable users, by changing your account settings.

## Disclosure of your personal data – outside Chessable

We may disclose your personal data to:

  * our agents and service providers (including our payment services providers); 
    * **Amazon Web Services** \- E-mail campaigns
    * **Kualo** \- Secure web hosting
    * **Google Analytics** \- Anonymised aggregated statistics
    * **Google Optimize** \- Split testing
    * **Facebook** \- I.P. Address for Like/share buttons
    * **Frontapp.com** \- Customer support
    * **Mailchimp** \- E-mail campaigns
    * **Paypal** \- Payment gateway
    * **Quaderno** \- Tax and invoicing software
    * **Stripe** \- Payment gateway
    * **StumbleUpon** \- I.P. Address for Stumble buttons
    * **SupportHero.io** \- Provide a helpful knowledge base + contact form
    * **Xero** \- Accounting and invoicing software
    * **Twitter** \- I.P. Address for Tweet button
    * **Zapier** \- Automation software, produce instant-activations and invoices *removed on 5th Oct 2018*
  * other companies within our group;
  * our payment processors;

Basically,

In some cases, we may need to send your data to authorised others outside of Chessable.

## Keeping your data secure

We will use appropriate technical and organisational measures to safeguard your personal data, for example:

  * access to your account is controlled by a password and username that are unique to you; and
  * we store your personal data on secure servers.

While we will use all reasonable efforts to safeguard your personal data, you acknowledge that the use of the internet is not entirely secure and for this reason we cannot guarantee the security or integrity of any personal data that are transferred from you or to you via the internet. It remains your responsibility to:

  * Ensure nobody else will use Chessable while you are logged into your account (we advise our users to take extra care when using public computers/devices and to NOT leave themselves logged in; it is your responsibility to ensure this does not happen);
  * Log out and exit your account on Chessable when you are not using it, on any private and/or public computer or device; and
  * Keep your password and any account details or access details secret and to yourself.

Our payment services provider may store your information outside the European Economic area, but do so with appropriate safeguards.

Basically,

We do what we can to keep your data secure, but at the end of the day no online service can ever guarantee 100% security.

## Profiling

We may use profiling techniques to propose to you certain content types or titles. We do this on the basis of your usage patterns of Chessable, including previous purchases.

## Use of cookies

A cookie is a small text file which is placed onto your computer (or other electronic device) when you access our website. We use cookies on Chessable to:

  * recognise you whenever you visit Chessable (this speeds up your access to the website as you do not have to log on each time);
  * obtain information about your preferences;
  * carry out research and statistical analysis to help improve our content, products and services and to help us better understand our visitor requirements and interests;
  * make your online experience more efficient and enjoyable.

The information we obtain from our use of cookies will not usually contain your personal data. Although we may obtain information about your computer or other electronic device such as your IP address, your browser and/or other internet log information, this will not usually identify you personally.

In most cases we will need your consent in order to use cookies on Chessable. The exception is where the cookie is essential in order for us to provide you with a service you have requested (e.g. to log in).

If you visit our website when your browser is set to accept cookies, we will interpret this as an indication that you consent to our use of cookies and other similar technologies as described in this Privacy Policy. If you change your mind in the future about letting us use cookies, you can modify the settings of your browser to reject cookies or disable cookies completely.

Basically,

The site uses cookies. This section tells you what they are, what they’re for, and how to change your settings to remove them.

## Description of cookies

The table below is designed to provide more information about the cookies we use and why:

Name of cookie | Owner | Purpose for the cookie  
---|---|---  
3 Login Cookies | Chessable | These cookies allow us to remember that you are logged in to the service. Without them, your computer may have trouble remaining logged in.  
Promotional Cookie | Chessable | This cookie allows us to show you special offers or sales we may conduct, only as often as you'd like to see them. Once you dismiss the offer, the cookie allows us to remember you've done so. Without this cookie, we may not be able to remember you've seen the promotion and display it to you again. For instance, our Black Friday sales.  
"Cookie" Cookie | Chessable | This cookie allows us to stop showing you the "this site uses cookies" notice.  
Stripe Cookie | Stripe | If you have used Stripe as our payment provider, the may set up cookies to facilitate the service. More information is in their own [Cookie Policy](https://stripe.com/cookies-policy/legal).  
Google Analytics | Google | This is a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc which uses cookies to show us how visitors found and explored our site, and how we can enhance their experience. It provides us with anonymised information about the behaviour of our visitors (e.g., how long they stayed on the site, the average number of pages viewed) and also tells us how many visitors we have had.  
  
Chessable may also use 3rd party vendor re-marketing tracking, by means of Facebook Ads and Google Adwords tracking cookies. This means we may show ads to you across the internet, specifically on Facebook and the Google Content Network (GCN). As always we respect your privacy and are not collecting any identifiable information through the use of these remarketing systems.

Basically,

Here is a list of all the cookies we use on the site, and their purpose.

## How to turn off cookies

If you do not want to accept cookies, you can change your browser settings so that cookies are not accepted. If you do this, please be aware that you may lose some of the functionality of Chessable. For further information about cookies and how to disable them please go to:   
[www.aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/) or [www.allaboutcookies.org](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/). 

To opt out of Google Analytics, visit this webpage - <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

The third-party vendors, including Google, whose services we use – will place cookies on web browsers in order to serve ads based on past visits to our website. – Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user’s prior visits to your website. This allows us to make special offers and continue to market our services to those who have shown interest in our service.

Basically,

Here is how you can turn off cookies, but your Chessable account might not operate as you expect due to the technological limitations this entails.

## Information about other individuals

If you give us information on behalf of someone else, you confirm that the other person has appointed you to act on his/her behalf and has agreed that you can:

  * give consent on his/her behalf to the processing of his/her personal data;
  * receive on his/her behalf any data protection notices;

## Do not use Chessable for private and sensitive data

Chessable is a tool to help you improve your chess learning. We do not wish for Chessable to be used for the processing of any sensitive data. Do not use Chessable (including its messaging function) to share with any user any personal contact information like your phone number or street address. Do not use Chessable to send or store any item revealing racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, or trade union membership, and the processing of genetic data, biometric data for the purpose of uniquely identifying a natural person, data concerning health or data concerning a natural person's sex life or sexual orientation.

Basically,

Please keep sensitive information, like race, gender, sexual orientation and other such data off the site. Chessable is a site strictly to learn and improve your chess.

## Links to Other Sites

Chessable does and may contain links to other websites. This privacy policy applies only to our website, [www.chessable.com](https://www.chessable.com/), so when you visit other websites please read their privacy policies, as we cannot accept any responsibility for breaches or issues you may have in relation to privacy once you leave our website.

Basically,

We may link to other websites, and while we do our best to curate links, we can't be responsible for them.

## What is the Legal Basis for Our Processing Your Personal Data

In some cases, the legal basis for the processing of your personal data is your consent. This is the case, for example, if you agree to us emailing you with marketing information. Any consent you provide may be withdrawn at any time by emailing [hello@chessable.com](mailto:hello@chessable.com).

In other cases, the processing will be necessary for the purposes of our providing you with the Services as referred to in our Terms of Use. 

Also, we may process personal data in accordance with our legitimate interest in engaging in providing and developing our services to you and other users – provided that those interests are not outweighed by your rights and interests. If you think that your rights and interests do outweigh our legitimate interests in providing our services, please let us know by emailing us at [hello@chessable.com](mailto:hello@chessable.com).

We may also process your data where:

This is necessary to allow us to comply with our legal obligations; or processing is necessary in order to protect your vital interests (for example your human rights); or processing is necessary for us to perform tasks that are of public interest or in the exercise of official authority.

If you have previously given consent to our processing your data (for example, in relation to our sending you marketing information by email) you can freely withdraw such consent at any time. You can do this by emailing us at [hello@chessable.com](mailto:hello@chessable.com). If you do withdraw your consent, and if we do not have another legal basis for processing your information, then we will stop processing your personal data. If we do have another legal basis for processing your information, then we may continue to do so subject to your legal rights. More details about your data protection rights are set out in the Your Rights section below.

Basically,

We process your data only with your consent, or where there is another valid legal basis to do so. Please e-mail us if you'd like to revoke consent.

## Where we store your data

The personal data we collect is stored on our own servers and that of our service providers who help power the Chessable service.

Some of our service providers are based outside the European Economic Area, in countries which may have different data privacy norms than those which apply to us in the UK. If we transfer or store your information outside the EEA in this way, we will take steps to ensure that your privacy rights continue to be protected as required by UK data protection laws.

Basically,

We store your data on our UK servers, but sometimes we may need to transfer it abroad to service providers who help us make things happen. In all cases, we safeguard and protect your data.

## Your rights

You may choose not to provide us with personal data and you may turn off cookies in your browser by changing its settings. If you make these decisions, you may continue to browse the pages of chessable.com. However, we will not be able to provide you with the Chessable service.

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes.

You have the right to access information we hold about you, together with an explanation of the categories of data being processed, the purposes of such processing, and the categories of third parties to whom the data may be disclosed. You can also require us to provide you details of the period for which the data will be stored (or the criteria used to determine that period) and information about your other rights regarding our use of your data. We will provide you with the information within one month of your request, unless doing so would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others. That would include, for example, another person’s confidentiality or intellectual property rights. We’ll tell you if we can’t meet your request for that reason. If you wish to exercise this right, please send a request to [hello@chessable.com](mailto:hello@chessable.com).

You also have the following rights:

  * The right to require us to rectify any inaccurate personal data concerning you.
  * The right to be ‘forgotten’ by us and have us erase any personal data we hold about you, if it is no longer necessary for us to hold the data for purposes of your use of the Service.
  * The right to object to us using your data for the purposes of profiling you or making automated decisions about you. We may use your data to determine whether we should let you know information about the Service which might be relevant to you. Otherwise, the only circumstances in which we will do this is to provide you with the Chessable service.
  * The right to ask us to port your data to another service (if technically feasible) or to provide you with a copy of data we hold about you in a structured, commonly used machine-readable format so that you can provide it to them. We will do so to the extent that we are required to under applicable laws, but not to the extent that this involves disclosing data about any other individual.
  * You can also exercise these rights at any time by contacting us at [hello@chessable.com](mailto:hello@chessable.com). To the extent that it does not involve disproportionate effort on our part, if you exercise any of the above rights we will tell any third parties to whom we have passed your data.

Additionally, you have the right to lodge a complaint regarding our use of your data. You should address any complaint to the Information Commissioner’s Office, either by calling their helpline on 0303 123 1113 or as directed on their website at [www.ico.org.uk](https://www.ico.org.uk/).

Basically,

You can ask us for a copy of the data we hold about you. You can also ask to be excluded from any of our services if you desire.

## How long we keep your data

We will retain personal data for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.

## Other Important Provisions

You can read more about data protection law by visiting the Information Commissioner's website.

If we change our Privacy Policy, we will post any changes on this page. You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes to this policy. We will notify you of any material changes to this policy, by email and by a notification in your Chessable account seen immediately upon login at the top right of your page.

Basically,

We may update and improve our privacy policy from time to time. You should check this page for updates, although we will do our best to let you know via e-mail and notification of any changes.

## Our contact details

We welcome your feedback and questions. If you wish to contact us, please send an email to hello@chessable.com or you can write to us at 20-22 Wenlock Road, London, United Kingdom, N1 7GU.

We are a limited company registered in England & Wales, and our registered office is at 20-22 Wenlock Road, London, United Kingdom, N1 7GU.

Basically,

We love to hear from our users, please write to us.

This is Version 3, updated on 1st of May, 2018. Single provider removal on the 5th of October, 2018.

**Archived old versions, not legally binding:**

Version 2, on the 12th of March, 2018. Reason for Change: Updated our service providers in light of recent GDPR guidance.

Version 1, on the 12th of July, 2017. Reason for Change: Updated to comply with GDPR.
